It's Shikeripechim!
シケリペチムだ
シケリペチムが攻めて来たぞー！
Shikeripechim is attacking!
でえっ！
きゃあーあっ！
つりやあっ！
うえいっ
のおあっ
のおっ
That's as far as you go!
そこまでだ！
Take aim!
構えっ！
引けーい！
Retreat!
Fire!
撃てーえっ！
うおーくっ
でえーえ えっ くそおっ！
Damn!
kodomo no goro no yume wa
The dream I had when I was a child,
子供の頃の夢は 色褪せない落書きで
iroase nai rakugaki de
were drawn to my heart's desire
omou mama kaki suberasete
with scribbles that wouldn't fade away
思うまま書き滑らせて
描く未来へとつながる
egaku mirai he to tsunagaru
and are connected to the future i draw.
Utawarerumono
sumiwataru sora
The clear skies
澄み渡る空 果てしないほど青く
hateshinai hodo aoku
were endlessly blue.
mujaki na kokoro ni
And my innocent heart,
無邪気な心に 充たされ魅かれてく
mitasare hikareteku
being satisfied, was attracted to them.
yagate jiyuu ni tobimawareru
I finally obtained wings
やがて自由に飛びまわれる
翼(はね)を手に入れて
hane wo teni irete
with which I could fly freely.
muku na hitomi wa motometeku
I want to go to the end of the skies
無垢な瞳は求めてく
空の向こうへ 行きたいな
sora no mukou he ikitai na
which my pure eyes desire.
kore tonai negai kara
If one wish could be granted
止め処ない願いから 一つだけ叶うのなら
hitotsu dake kanau no nara
out of countless others...
dare ni mo yuzuri taku wa nai
I feel that it should be to grab onto a dream
誰にも譲りたくはない
夢を掴みたいと思うよ
yume wo tsukamitai to omou yo
and never be tempted to let go.
kodomo no goro no yume wa
The dreams I had when I was a child,
子供の頃の夢は 色褪せない落書きで
iroase nai rakugaki de
were drawn eternally,
itsuwademo kaki tsuzukerareta
with scribbles that wouldn't fade away
いつまでも描き続けられた
願う未来へとつながる
negau mirai he to tsunagaru
and are connected to the future I wish for.
The Ravages of War
We may have repelled the Shikeripechim army so far,
一旦は退いたシケリペチム軍勢ですが
but, as we speak, they have stationed
themselves just outside our borders.
なお国境周辺にとどまっています
奴らに焼き討ちされた集落も
二つや三つじゃねえ
They haven't razed just two or three villages either.
犠牲も相当な数だ
There's been a large number of lives lost.
We won't let them get away with this.
このままでは済まさん！
We'll pay them back a hundred times over!
何百倍にして返してやる！
Are you implying that we should
invade Shikeripechim?
それは こちらからシケリペチムに
攻め込むという事ですか？
Of course! Isn't that right, Brother?
無論だ！ そうだろ 兄者？
Brother?
兄者？
We will concentrate on defense for now.
今は守りに徹する
Intensify our watch along the border.
みんなは 国境の警戒を強めてくれ
What!?
Defense only?
守るだけ？
Why, Brother!?
何故だ？ 兄者！
It is His Highness's decision.
聖上の決定ですよ
えっええっ…
I have brought Touka-san.
トウカさんをお連れしました
If you are releasing me from my cell,
牢から出したという事は
does this mean you have
decided on my sentence?
某の処分が決まったのですな
I am ready to face my fate.
覚悟はできております
Misunderstanding though it may have been,
誤解とは言え
罪無き人々を苦しめたのは確か
the fact remains that I have caused
innocent people much suffering.
If taking my head will erase my sins...
某の首一つで償えるならば…
無用だ
That will be unnecessary.
Eruruu...
エルルゥ
Yes?
はい
I return this to you.
お返しします
But after what I've done to you...
しかし 某はそなた達の…
We have no reason to despise you.
恨む理由がありません
It was all a sad misunderstanding.
全ては悲しい誤解だったのですから
I must make amends!
償いはせねばなりませぬ
It is not your time to die yet.
死ぬのは早い
貴公には まだ成すべき事がある
There is still something for you to do.
Benawi...
ベナウィ
I shall return King Orikakan to you.
オリカカン王をお返しする
故郷の土に還してあげられよ
Take his body back to its homeland.
The one responsible for this crime
is the man who misled you.
罪は あなた達を
扇動した者が負うべきものだ
King Orikakan was but one of
his unfortunate victims.
オリカカン王も
哀れな犠牲者の１人であった
あはぁ…
A message, Sire!
申し上げますっ！
へーはあっ へーはあ　へーっ
Shikeripechim's forces have once again crossed
our border and have resumed their invasion!
シケリペチムの軍勢が
再び国境より侵入を開始しましたっ！
出るぞ！
We're moving out! Oboro! Kurou!
オボロ！ クロウ！
Sire!
おうっ！
Farewell, Lady Touka.
さらばだ トウカ殿
谷を抜ければ目標の集落か
So the village we're heading for
is beyond the valley?
トゥスクルなど一飲みにすればいいものを
We should just wipe out all of Tuskuru!
Niwe-sama must surely have
his reasons for this.
ニウェ様には
何かお考えがあっての事でしょう
We can only trust him then?
信じるのみか
Huh?
Tuskuru forces!
トゥスクルです
面白い こうでなくてはな
Interesting, now this is what we need!
Give the whole army orders to attack!
Wipe them all out!
全軍に突撃命令だ！
一気に叩き潰せーっ！
Yes, sir!
What the...
何？
Blue Team, take aim!
青組構えっ！
Red Team, take aim!
赤組構えっ！
Fire!
撃てーっ！
ううっ えーい 隊を乱すなーっ！
Don't break rank!
ええいっ ふっ！
ぬおっ！
その首 貰ったーっ！
You're mine!
Not so fast, kid!
粋がるな小僧ぉーっ！
My lord!
若様ーっ！
That was too reckless of you, my lord.
無茶し過ぎです 若様
おお お おいっ う うわああーっ！
Looks like we've driven them back.
どうやら撃退したか
Message!
伝令ーっ！ へえっ はあっ はっ
The Shikeripechim are invading
on our western border!
西の国境に シケリペチムが進行中です！
You must change course immediately!
直ちに転進を！
From the west now!?
今度は 西だと？
でやあっ だあっ！
ええーえっ！
ふんっ うっ
へえっ てうーっ！
The enemy are few!
相手は少数！
Pound them into the ground in one sweep!
このまま一気に押し潰してしまえーっ！
Huh?
は 背後から敵襲です！
The enemy is attacking from the rear!
Damn them!
おんのれー
奴らに攻撃できる程の兵がいたのかっ
They have enough men to launch
a pincer attack?
It can't be! Just one person!?
バカな たった１人だと？
こっ この化け物めーっ！
You damned freak!
That's pretty rude.
失礼ですわ
ううーわあっ！
ああ わ わあ… わああーっ
After them! Don't let any get away!
追撃ーっ！
１人も逃がすなーっ！
Good work.
ご苦労さん
Wasn't much work at all.
別に苦労などしてませんわ
Want some?
やります？
はえーよ
It's too early for that!
I'll help myself after we
clean these guys up.
全部片付いてから 遠慮なくな
いいっきうっ ふっうっ
いいーっいっ！
うっくっ！ ううっふっ！
-あらがったふっ！
-だあっ！
-ぬあっ
-ぬうーいへっ！
のあっ！ ぐう うっ
You've had it!
とどめだ！
ううーってっ！
Splendid.
見事だ
I understand that you were a
samurai general in Kuccha Keccha.
クッチャケッチャでは
侍大将を勤めていたそうだな
Yes, I ask that you allow me to join
your forces, as promised.
はっ！ お約束通り
配下に加えて頂きますよう お願い致します！
Promise? Very well.
約束か
良かろう
ふんっ！
-ああ…
-願いは叶えて取らす
I shall grant you your wish.
Take him to the place.
例の所へ連れて行ってやれ
I have gathered the materials,
as you wished.
望み通りに素材は揃えた
The rest will depend on how
you put it all together.
あとは貴様の料理次第という事だな
But none of these men have
sufficed to entertain me.
だが どいつもこいつも
ワシを楽しませるには物足らぬ
I guess that man is the only one
I can expect so much from.
やはり期待できるのは あの男だけか
クックックック 待ち通しいわ
I can hardly wait.
I want to see his true form soon.
奴の本性 早く見たいものよ
クーックッヘッヘ
カーッカッカッカッカッカハッハッハッハ
The number of enemy attacks
is increasing daily.
敵の襲撃は 日を追って増えて来ています
They're sure keeping us in suspense.
これじゃあ ヘビの生殺しだあ
Why don't they just attack us
in one, fell swoop?
何故一気に攻めて来ねえ？
Many of our men are injured,
and they are all quite exhausted.
怪我人も多いですし
さすがにみんな疲れてきています
That is probably one of the enemy's goals.
それが狙いの一つでしょう
By repeating these skirmishes over and over,
小競り合いを繰り返し
我々を精神的にも肉体的にも
疲弊させるつもりです
they plan to wear us down
physically and mentally.
Might there be any other reasons?
では他にも狙いが？
To incite us.
挑発…
It is likely.
恐らく
Well, that's interesting!
面白いじゃないか！
兄者 こっちから攻め込んでやるか？
Shall we take the offensive then, Brother?
Shikeripechim has more than ten times
the might of our own country.
シケリペチムの国力は 我が国の10倍以上
まともにぶつかって
勝てる相手ではないでしょう
We cannot hope to win by taking
them on directly.
We won't know that unless we try!
そんなの
やってみなけりゃ分からないだろう！
攻めるべきだっ 兄者！
We should attack them, Brother!
We will wait for now.
今は待つのだ
Wait? For what?
待つって何をですかい？
At this rate, we'll be the first to give in.
このままじゃ こっちが先に
参っちまいやすぜ？
That's right! I don't want to go
along with their intentions!
そうだ！ やつらの思い通りに
なるなんてごめん
We will wait!
待つのだ
There is probably only one way
that we can win.
恐らく我々が勝てる策は
たった一つしかないだろう
Only one way we can win?
たった一つの勝てる策？
I cannot say what that is right now.
今は言えん
敵に気取られては その勝機すら失う
If the enemy gets wind of it, we will lose
even that small chance of victory.
I want you to trust me and follow along.
私を信じて付いて来て欲しい
フン 元よりそうさ
That goes without saying!
We will follow you, Brother.
That's all there is to it.
俺達は兄者に付いていく
それだけだ
あは…
What of the others?
みんなは？
解散しました
They have left.
I see...
そうか
Things are moving quickly, aren't they?
流れが速いですね
Too quickly.
速すぎる
I told them to trust me.
私を信じろか…
One word from me and the fate
of this nation is sealed.
私の言葉一つで
この国のみんなの明日が決まる
I know that that word will
only bring more pain.
それが更に多くの苦難を強いると
分かっているのに…
Eruruu...
エルルゥ
I only wanted to defend those I love,
私はこれまで 好きな人達を…
the lives of everyone.
みんなの暮らしを守りたくて
戦い続けて来た
That is why I have been fighting,
なのに戦は終わらない
but the fighting won't end.
そればかりか この国を
新たな戦雲に包もうとしている
Instead, the threat of yet another
war looms over this country.
What am I doing?
私のしている事は何なのだ？
Where am I heading?
私はどこに向かっているのだ？
I don't know.
私には…
分かりません
All I know is that I believe in you.
私に分かるのは
ハクオロさんを
信じているという事だけです
Always, no matter what happens, without fail.
どんな時でも 何があっても… 絶対に
Eruruu...
エルルゥ…
I have great misgivings.
私は不安なんだ
ふえーあ！ やあーっ！ はあーっ！
Put them to rout!
蹴ー散らせーっ！
うっ うっ うわっ おお ううーわぁ
ハッハッハッ 他愛もない！
This is too easy.
ぬっ！ おわっ！
They brought in water and
created a sea of mud.
水を引き込んで泥沼を作っておいたのか
Brother's tactics are always on target.
兄者の策略はさすがだな
It's almost amusing how badly they fell for it.
笑えるぐらいはまってくれる
Yes, but... Even though we've
been winning every battle,
ですが 連戦連勝なのに
まるで勝っている気がしません
we don't really seem to be
winning the war at all.
My lord, how long must we go on
fighting like this?
若様 いつまでこのような戦いを
続ければいいのですか？
We can only do what we must.
俺達は 俺達のするべき事をするだけだ
だあーっ！ おおっ！
And so the enemy's resistance is
greater than we expected.
といった次第で
敵の抵抗は思いのほか激しく
Fine!
良い
I say that things are going fine
just as they are.
今のままで良いと言ったのだ
抗えば抗う程 奴は追い詰められていく
The more he fights, the more he
drives himself into a corner.
Order the armies to continue
their offensive tactics!
兵にはそのまま攻め立てよと申しつけい
Yes, Sire!
ははあっ
ぐうはあっ ぎぎいっえーっ
ぎえっえっ！
Full of fight, aren't you?
元気が良いのお
その様子なら
ここから出られる日も近かろう
Given that, I'd say you will be
getting out of here soon.
良い 良いぞ ヒッハッハッハッハッハッハ
Good, very good!
Oh, it's you.
おお 貴様か
仕上がりは上々ではないか
They're coming along very nicely.
その手腕 褒めて取らせるぞ
I must praise your skill.
You will have as many subjects
as battles continue,
素材は戦の数だけ集まる
but know that quality is more
important than quantity.
だがな 重要なのは量より質よ
His name was Hakuoro, wasn't it?
I liked him the moment I saw him.
ハクオロとか言ったな
あの男 一目で気に入ったわ
He will surely meet my expectations.
ワシの期待に必ず応えてくれよう
I will prepare any number of
sacrifices for him!
そのための贄なら
いくらでも用意してくれる
クヮーッカッカッカッカッカッハッハッハ
Eruruu-neesama, over here too!
エルルゥ姉様 こっちにも！
Yes! Aruruu, go get the new one off the shelf.
アルルゥ
棚に入ってる新しいのを取って来て
Aruruu!
アルルゥ！
I'm all right.
大丈夫っ
They're at their limit.
もう限界ですね
The soldiers are at the peak of exhaustion.
兵達の疲労は頂点に達しつつあります
No matter how many times we win,
we cannot avoid losing more of them.
どんなに勝っても 犠牲は避けられません
If the battles continue like this...
このまま戦が続けば…
The time has come, my elite troops.
我が精鋭達よ
時は満ちた！
No matter how cunning they may be,
we are clearly more powerful!
いくら小賢しい知恵を働かせようと
力の差は歴然である！
There is no need for intricate
tactics in a huge army.
大群に区々たる用兵など必要ない
Don't think at all!
何も考えるな
Just burn everything and kill everyone!
ただひたすら焼き尽くし殺し尽くせーっ！
I am waiting for you.
待っておるぞ
クアーッカッカッカッカ
The enemy is making a full-scale offensive.
敵の総攻撃です
国境全域へ 同時侵攻を開始しました
They have begun a coordinated advance
all along the border.
Is their entire army across our border?
国境に敵は全軍か？
No, there appears to be a difference
in speed of their advancing units,
いいえ
進軍の速度に差があるらしく 全てとは…
so I don't believe it's their whole army.
Brother?
兄者？
There is only one way we can win this battle.
我々が勝てる唯一の策
We must draw Shikeripechim's
whole army into this country,
それは 敵の全軍をこの国に引き付け
in effect emptying their
country of its forces.
シケリペチム本国をカラにする事だ
そして別働隊が
シケリペチム本城に攻め入り
Then a detached force of ours will
charge into Shikeripechim castle
and take Niwe's head.
ニウェの首を取る
There is no other way.
それ以外に策は無い！
However, the varying speed of their advance
has caused an unforeseen miscalculation.
しかし 進軍速度の差が
思わぬ誤算を生んでしまった
But at this rate...
でも このままでは…
迎え撃つ
We will face them head on.
Sire?
聖上
心配するな
Do not worry.
We can still ward off this attack.
この１戦ならば まだ支えきれる
We still can.
まだな
Benawi, you will take the cavalry.
ベナウィにはラクシャライを預ける
Advance from the west and cut off
the enemy's supplies.
西から回り込み 敵の補給線を断て
If the enemy's progress is uneven,
it should be possible.
敵の足並みが乱れているなら可能なはずだ
Yes, Sire.
はい
城はウルトリィに任せる
I will leave the castle to Urutori.
Oboro, Kurou and Karula will come with me.
オボロとクロウ カルラは私と共に
国境からの敵を迎え撃つ
We will battle the enemy coming
across the border.
Any of the wounded who can move
will join in the battle.
負傷した者も動ける限りは出陣して貰う
But...
そんなっ
I know it is unreasonable.
Please understand.
みんな承知だ 分かってくれ
Don't falter! Attack!
ひるむな！ 突っ込めーっ！
のわーっ おわーっ！
This is hard work.
骨の折れる事ですわ
Faster, go faster!
速く… もっと速く！
てやー！ くあーっ てやっ！ うあっ
Gura!
グラァ！
Now!
いーまだーっ！
だあーっ！
ふっ ぐっ でやあーっ！
My lord!
若様っ！
Where is my brother?
兄者は？
ごわあっ
とぅあっ！ ふんっ！
ぬうーっ！
Eruruu!
エルルゥ！
Yes! Now, stay with us.
はいっ
あとを離れないで下さい
I see that is Hakuoro there.
そこにいるのはハクオロと見た
I shall make a name for myself
by slaying you!
討ち取って我が誉れとせん！
Get him!
かかれーっ！
-でやああーっ！
-ぐしっ！ ううんっ！
どわあっ
I shall repay my debt by assisting you.
義により助太刀致す
Why?
何故？
貴殿の計らいで
オリカカン王は故郷の土に還り申した
Thanks to your gracious arrangements, I was
able to return King Orikakan to his homeland.
It is a custom of the Evankulga
to repay honor with honor.
義には義で応えるのが
エヴェンクルガの習わし
It would be my honor and privilege
to serve you from now on.
以後は 末席に加えて頂きとうございます
あはあ…
貴様ぁ 寝返りおったか
Damn you... So, you've turned traitor, eh?
I am no traitor.
寝返りとは聞き捨てならん
I am simply repaying a debt.
義に応えたまでの事
Know that it is Niwe, who is a coward
for deceiving King Orikakan!
オリカカン王を欺いたニウェこそ
卑劣の名に値すると知れ
Enough of your babbling!
ほざきおってー！
Enemy general, I shall take your life!
敵将！ その首貰い受けるっ！
ふぬんっ
こはあっ
うううっ　ううう　おわあっ　あああー
You were a great help.
助かったぞ
ありがとうございました
Thank you very much.
いえ… 駆けつけるのが遅くなって
申し訳ありませぬ
On the contrary, I am sorry
for getting here so late.
-あはーっはーはーっ
-あっ
-あっ はっ
-エルルゥ！
Eruruu!
Don't worry, I'll save her!
大丈夫 今助けるから
うひぅーっ！
私はもう… 無理です
I'm not going to make it.
この子だけでも…
Save my child...
そんな事 言ってはダメッ！
You mustn't say that!
この子には お母さんが必要なんです！
This child needs his mother!
Eruruu!
エルルゥ！
-なあーっ！
-ううーっ
なあっ ふっ！
-ううっ…
-やっ… ぐふうっ
Please, my child...
お願い この子を！
It's no good!
ダメです！
や… があっ！
No!
いやあーっ！
うっふうふうーっ　うっふうああーっ
I'm sorry, I'm sorry...
ゴメンね ゴメンねっ！
Shikeripechim's forces have
retreated to the border.
シケリペチムは国境まで退きました
What damage have we incurred?
被害は？
Many of the villages were burned,
and many of our people have perished.
多くの集落が焼かれ
民の犠牲も相当な数に達しています
俺の隊も半数がやられちまった
Half of my unit is gone.
Brother...
兄者…
Next time, the enemy will probably
attack with their full force.
次こそは 敵も全軍で攻めて来るだろう
Benawi, I will leave most of
our troops with you.
ベナウィに兵のほとんどを預ける
私は少数の精鋭をもって
敵の城へと乗り込む
I will take a few of our elite and
march on the enemy castle.
That's too dangerous!
それは危険過ぎますぜ！
I am aware of that,
承知の上だ
but there is no other way.
だが これしか策は無い
Karula and Touka will come with me.
カルラとトウカは私と共に
Oboro and Kurou, I want you to help Benawi.
オボロとクロウは ベナウィを助けてくれ
Sire...
聖上
Will I kill Niwe first,
or will we all be massacred before that?
私がニウェを討つのが先か
全滅するのが先か…
It will be a fight against time.
これは 時間との戦いになる
We are moving out.
出陣します
Let's go.
出るぞ
炎さえも凍てついた
honou sae mo itetsuita
I seek the solitude
kokuno naka moto mu
that freezes even flames.
孤独の中求む
魂から結びつき 私を恋い温めて
tamashi kara musubitsuki
Connecting with your soul,
watashi wo koi atatamete
warm me with your love.
嗚呼 祈りの言葉がふるえ
a inori no kotoba ga furue
Ah...the words of prayer tremble...
嗚呼 弱きいのちが消えても
a yowaki no chika kiete mo
Ah even if the faint-hearted
were to disappear...
くりかえす 輪廻の流れ辿り
kurikaesu innen no nagare tadori
Following the recurring paths of fate.
終わらない世界の宿命を見つめてる
owaranai sekai no shukumei wo mitsumeteru
I gaze upon the never-ending world's destiny.
くりかえし 詠われる者達よ
kurikaeshi utawareru mono tachi yo
Oh the ones being sung continuously
守られてまどろむ宵
mamorarete madoromu you ni
be protected and sleep.
The End of the Banquet